

Vipin Kumar Dinkar

131 TAIMOOR NAGAR, NEW FRIENDS COLONY, MAHARANI BAGH, South Delhi, Delhi, 110025, India

- ✓ vipinkumard365@gmail.com
- **** 09871633867
- NicestRudeGuy
- ykd linkin

SKILLS

JavaScript

React.js & Next.js 8

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$

Node.js

WordPress

SQL

PHP

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$

CSS & SCSS

BootStrap & **TailWind**

INTERESTS

Music

Gaming

Photography

Traveling

LANGUAGES

English

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$

Hindi

10

lacksquare

A **Lead Engineer** 5+ years of corporate and freelance experience. I've worked on MERN, LAMP & WORDPRESS Stacks over the years. Hired and mentored several engineers. I am IOT, Cloud & Block Chain enthusiast. Have worked on Open source projects like Brackets (Code Editor), rtMedia (WP Multimeda plugin with 20k+ active users), Gutenberg (blocks). Also got a chance to show my skills at Google's Projects AMP and WP WebStories.

WORK EXPERIENCE

lisr

(01/04/2023 -Present)

(01/06/2021 -

30/09/2021)

Senior Software

Engineer

Lead team to build Dynamic Design System Migration of DS to Various Front End Apps Migration of WebPack to Vite for several Front **End Apps Team Management** Hiring new engineers Code Review

https://www.jisr.net

Accern

Senior Software Engineer

Added new features to the NLP platform. Added Cypress Testing and Git hooks for code checking. Added SonarQube for Static Code analysis. Implemented Several Dashboards and Bug fixes to existing Platform. Added WebPack optimization and Lazy Loading of components. Mentored Several engineers to give best UI/UX.

(01/11/2021 -

(01/09/2020 -

31/03/2021)

06/01/2023)

https://accern.com

10up

Front End Engineer

Worked upon Traditional WP site theme, plugin and gutenberg development for PK Global (Aquired by concentrix). Build several react component and Gutenberg blocks for VmWare's Headless Site.

https://10up.com

Front End Engineer

rtCamp

Worked upon several Gutenberg blocks for rtmedia pro plugins (Gutenberg Blocks). Worked on Rolling Stone React Native App. Created Headless WP websites for better and faster UI/UX (WaldosFriends). Created POC for Google's AMP DB and its successful launch (Google POC).

https://rtcamp.com

Freelance

Web

Developer

Developed custom inventory management and business sites using LAMP stack. Also built several Traditional WP site from scratch (Theme and Plugin development).

Campk12

(01/06/2020 - 31/08/2020)

IS Teacher

Taught school kids CSE and Js https://campk12.com

EDUCATION

USICT, GGSIPU

Engineering

MCA(se), Software

(01/08/2017 -

01/08/2020)

(01/01/2017 -

01/12/2018)

JIMS,VK BCA, Software Engineering

(01/08/2014 -01/08/2017) 7.4

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Covid Relief (01/04/2020 - 01/06/2020)

Helper

REFERENCES

Gautam Jha Friend

SDE2 @ Brightly

\$802191242

Mehar Kaila Friend

SDE2 @ Swiggy

■ gautamjha.mailbox@gmail.com

Hitesh Aloney

Friend

SDE4 @ Baazi Games

9870443933

Gaurav Kumar Singh

Colleague

SDE3 @ Accern **\$143810766**

9999771391

■ mehar0kaila@gmail.com